A Guide to the Rosenthal Collection of Historical Portraits ca.[1880-1900]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1899, 1 of 4 states present; no.19 of 25 sets; signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:14)
  "Twenty five sets in three states of this plate printed and subscribed for by ... No. 25 Albert Rosenthal." "Pencil sketch of General Washington, from life taken by Chas. Willson Peale 1787"
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1898, 1 of 4 states present; no.25 of 25 sets. (Box-folder 3:15)
  "Twenty five sets in four states of this plate printed and subscribed for by ... No. 19 Jacob E. Barr."
  "From the watercolor by James Peale, drawn from life, Philadelphia 1795, in the possession of Charles Henry Hart, Esq., Phila."
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1896, Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 3:16)
  "James Ramage pinx."
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 3:17)
  A miniature version after James Ramage?
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1902, 2 of 4 states present; 1 state numbered 25 of 25 sets. (Box-folder 3:18)
  "The edition of this plate is limited to 24 sets in 4 states of the plate. Subscribed for by ... 25. Albert Rosenthal."
  After St. Memin.
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1899, 1 of 4 states present; no. 16 of 25 sets. (Box-folder 3:19)
  "Twenty five sets in four states of this plate printed and subscribed for by ... 16. William H. Patterson."
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1900, 4 of 4 states present; no. 16 of 25 sets. (Box-folder 3:20)
  "Twenty five sets in four states of this plate printed and subscribed for by ... 16. Jacob E. Barr."
  After Sharples.
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 and Washington, Martha, 1731-1802 1900, 2 states present; both states signed by Albert Rosenthal; one or both possibly proofs. (Box-folder 3:21)
  "From the paintings by John Trumbull in the National Museum, Washington, D.C."
- Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796 1902, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:22)
  "Charles Willson Peale pinx."
- Wayne, James Moore, 1790-1867 1890 (Box-folder 3:23)
- Weems, M. L. (Mason Locke), 1759-1825 n.d. (Box-folder 3:24)
  "From a print in the possession of D. Mc N. Stauffer, M. Inst. C.E."
- Weller, Samuel F. 1889 (Box-folder 3:25)
- West, Benjamin, 1738-1820 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 3:26)
  After Gilbert Stuart.
- West, Benjamin, 1738-1820 1887 (Box-folder 3:27)
  "From the original in the possession of the family"
- White, Edward Douglass, 1845-1921 1894 (Box-folder 3:28)
- Wickham, John, 1763-1839 n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 3:29)
- Wilcocks, Alexander, 1741-1801 n.d. (Box-folder 3:30)
  "From a miniature in the possession of Mrs. B. C. Wilcocks"
- Wilkinson, James, 1757-1825 n.d., Possibly a proof. (Box-folder 3:31)
  "C.W. Peale pinx."
- Williamson, Hugh, 1735-1819 1888 (Box-folder 3:32)
  "After painting by J. Trumbull" "From photograph of the original painting furnished by Dr. Thomas Addis Emmett"
- Wilson, James, 1742-1798 1890 (Box-folder 3:33)
- Wythe, George, 1726-1806 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:34)
  "From the original drawing by John Trumbull in the possession of Hon. James T. Mitchell"
- Wythe, George, 1726-1806 1888, Signed by Albert Rosenthal; "1 of ten proofs before lettering" in Rosenthal's hand. (Box-folder 3:35)
- Zachary, Lloyd, 1701-1756 n.d. (Box-folder 3:36)
  "From the original painting in the possession of the Penna. Hospital"